crystalski.co.uk 2017-06-17

# Data Protection | Crystal Ski

## Privacy policy

TUI UK Limited's Privacy Policy sets out what information we collect, how we collect it, and what we do with it. Our Privacy Policy applies to you and is available on our website and through other channels. In all your dealings with us you must ensure that others you represent are aware of the content of our Privacy Policy and consent to your acting on their behalf.

## INFORMATION ABOUT YOU

### Your Information

This refers to a combination of information such as your name, contact details, travel preferences and special needs/disabilities/dietary requirements that you supply us or is supplied to us, including your social preferences, interests and activities and any information about other persons you represent (such as those on your booking). Your information is collected when you request information from us, contact us (and vice versa), make a booking, use our website(s)/apps, link to or from our website(s)/apps, connect with us via social media and any other engagement we or our business partners have with you.

We will update your information whenever we can to keep it current, accurate and complete.

### Our Use of Your Information

  1. For the purpose of providing you with our services, including your flight, holiday, security, incident/accident management or insurance, etc., we may disclose and process your information outside the UK/EEA. In order for you to travel abroad, it may be mandatory (as required by government authorities at the point(s) of departure and/or destination) to disclose and process your information for immigration, border control, security and anti-terrorism purposes, or any other purposes which they determine appropriate. Some countries will only permit travel if you provide your advance passenger data (for example Caricom API and US secure flight data). These requirements may differ depending on your destination and you are advised to check. Even if not mandatory, we may exercise our discretion to assist where appropriate.
  2. We may collect and process your information for the purposes set out below and in our registration with the Office of the Information Commissioner, and disclose the same to our group companies for business purposes and also to companies and our service providers who act as "data processors" on our behalf, or to credit and fraud agencies (some of whom are located outside the UK/EEA). These purposes include administration, service, quality and improvement-related activities, customer care, product innovation and choice, business management, operation and efficiencies, re-organisation/structuring/sale of our business (or group companies), risk assessment/management, security, fraud and crime prevention/detection, monitoring, research and analysis, social media, reviews, advertising and marketing, loyalty programmes, profiling customer purchasing preferences, activities and trends, dispute resolution/litigation, credit checking and debt collection.
  3. Information (such as health or religion) may be considered "sensitive personal data" under the Data Protection Act 1998. We collect it to provide you with our services, cater to your needs or act in your interest, and we are only prepared to accept sensitive personal data on the condition that we have your positive consent. By booking with us you also agree for your insurers, their agents and medical staff to exchange relevant information and sensitive personal data with us in circumstances where we/they need to act on your behalf or in the interest of passengers or in an emergency.

**If you do not agree to Our Use of Your Information above, we cannot engage/do business with you or accept your booking.**

### Marketing Material

  1. Using your information, we may from time to time contact you with or make available to you (directly or indirectly) information on offers of goods and services, brochures, new products, forthcoming events or competitions from our holiday divisions and our group companies. We will tailor the information you receive or see; this will enable us to make available to you more personalised and relevant communications. We may use innovative technologies and work with business partners to achieve this.
  2. We will assume you agree to email when you make an e-booking or provide us with your email in other situations such as in-store, competitions, promotions, prize draws and social media.
  3. If you do not wish to receive such information or would like to change your preference, please refer to point 2 of "Your Rights" below.

### Your Rights

  1. On completing our Data Subject Access Request form, you are entitled to a copy of the information we hold about you (for a £10 fee) and to correct any inaccuracies.
  2. You have the right to ask in writing not to receive direct marketing material from us. If available, you can amend your previous preference on our website(s), use our "unsubscribe email", opt-out of personalised emails or refer to our literature containing instructions. Once properly notified by you, we will take steps to stop using your information in this way.
  3. For a list of relevant brands, please send us your request.

Please write to TUI UK Limited, Legal Department, TUI Travel House, Crawley Business Quarter, Fleming Way, Crawley, West Sussex RH10 9QL.

### Foreign Controls

Outside the European Economic Area (EEA), data protection controls may not be as strong as the legal requirements in this country.

## USE OF TOOLS/"COOKIES" AND LINKS TO OTHER WEBSITES

If our contact and dealing with you is via our website(s) or other e-platforms where our advertising is displayed, cookies may be used. To find out more about the types of cookies on our website(s), how we use cookies, to disable them or to change your preference and more, please refer to the information provided on our website(s). Other e-platforms may have different options and instructions. **By using our website(s), you consent to our use of cookies**.

Our website(s) may contain links to third party websites or micro-sites not controlled or owned by us. For example, reference sites or ancillary products and services sites or websites owned by our sister companies. It is your responsibility to check the status of these sites before using them. Please read their applicable terms and conditions, etc. carefully.

### What is a cookie?

Cookies are small files that are sent to your browser, for example Internet Explorer, Google Chrome or Firefox. They are stored on your computer's hard disk and only identify your computer, and not you personally.

The default location for these files is:  
**Windows** : c:\Documents and Settings\\{your_username}\Cookies  
**Mac** : Users\\{your_username}\Library\Cookies

There are two main purposes to cookies. The first is to add functionality like shopping carts, logging in as a particular user, remembering preferences and sharing links via social media. Secondly, cookies are used by website owners to collect usage data and provide personalised suggestions and information.

### How do we use cookies?

Cookies help to speed up the booking process so that you do not need to re-type the same information again and again. If you are making a purchase we will also use cookies to keep track of the transaction from one page to the next. We do not store any personal information in the cookie.

We also collect information relating to customer use and patterns. We use cookies and software tools to capture, measure and analyse site usage and related information.

When you are on our website, we use cookies to provide you with a more personal experience. In other words we use it to do things like remember what you've searched for (rather than typing it again when a new page loads) and to remember saved/recently searched accommodation. If you come back to the site at a later date then you'll be able to see any properties you have been researching recently.

When you are online but not using our website, to help us deliver advertising effectively and avoid repeating adverts, we work with carefully selected third parties who we allow to employ cookies on our site, on our behalf. These cookies allow us to provide advertising on other websites that are more relevant to a user's interests. The information that we collect and share is anonymous and not personally identifiable. It does not contain a user's name, address, telephone number or email address.

If you receive our emails, we tailor the information we send you based on the data our cookies have collected from your recent visits to our website. You can opt out of this in any marketing email we send.

Cookie function | Cookie name | Description  
---|---|---  
Application Cookies | BIGipServer | These cookies are generated by load balancers in our hosting cluster. They are used only to keep your site accesses on the same server in our cluster for the duration of your visit. This is a technical requirement relating to how our sites are constructed and is normal for many sites across the Internet.  
Site functionality | Saved Accommodation | This cookie stores which hotels you have chosen to save on this website, allowing you to easily return to a hotel that you've viewed recently.  
Site functionality | Recently Viewed Accommodation | This cookie stores which hotels you have been looking at on the site, allowing you to easily return to a hotel that you've viewed recently.  
Site functionality | Recent Searches | This cookie stores details of your recent searches and is used to display the "Recent Searches" feature on this website. This allows you to easily return to a search that you've made recently.  
Site functionality | Search Criteria | This cookie remembers your search criteria so that when a new page loads, you do not need to re-enter your search from the start.  
Site functionality | JSESSIONID | This cookie is set when you arrive at the website and is used to maintain your session on the website and to retain your last search criteria. Without this cookie you will not be able to use this website.  
Site functionality | Photo Competition | This cookie allows us to remember which photo you voted for and prevent fraudulent activity to artificially improve the results.  
Site functionality | Help (Get Satisfaction) | The cookies set for Get Satisfaction help to identify our account holders and keep track of your preferences. They use aggregated, anonymous data to measure total audience size and traffic as well as conduct research to improve the Get Satisfaction Service. See <http://getsatisfaction.com/privacy> for more details.  
Site Functionality | Client Login | Maintains a users session after logging into the client area post-booking.  
Site Functionality | WorldPay | Certain pages use the secure payment portal, WorldPay.  
Site Functionality  | Desktop/Mobile | This cookie remembers which version of the website you are viewing, desktop or mobile.  
Site Functionality | Feedback Survey | Similar to JSESSIONID this cookie is set when you arrive at the feedback part of the website. Without this cookie you will not be able to submit your feedback.  
Site Functionality | sIFR Flash Fonts | sIFR fonts are used within Flash. The cookie, sifrFetch, is set to indicate whether the browser supports Flash or not and therefore if sIFR fonts will work or not.  
Analytics | Adobe SiteCatalyst, comScore/Sitestat | These cookies enable us to collect aggregated visitor information including the number of visits and page views that arise from marketing activity. The data stored in these cookies is only used internally.  
Analytics | Tealeaf | These cookies contain data to analyse a user's actions across our website. The data stored in these cookies is only used internally.  
Analytics | ResponseTap (formerly Adinsight) | This cookie enables us to track the interaction between our website and sales centre to help us improve customer experience. The data collected is anonymous and only used internally.  
Analytics | Yahoo | These cookies enable us to collect anonymous, aggregated visitor information including the number of visits and page views that arise from marketing activity. The data stored in these cookies is only used internally.  
Analytics | Tagman, Tealium | We use Tagman and Tealium for tracking our marketing activity. The data collected is anonymous and only used internally.  
Analytics | Visual Website Optimizer | Visual Website Optimizer uses cookies to monitor performance of website design and function changes. The cookies are used to keep track of the Variation that a user has seen, the goals a user has completed and even the fact the user has become a part of the test or not. The data collected is anonymous and only used internally. More info: <http://visualwebsiteoptimizer.com/split-testing-blog/eu-cookie-law-implications/>  
Marketing | Search Engines: Google, Bing, Yahoo etc | The cookies used for search engines allow us to monitor and enhance the performance of marketing activity. The data collected is anonymous and only used internally.  
Marketing | Affiliates: Commission Junction, Affiliate Future | These cookies provide us with information to monitor the performance of specially selected marketers, advertisers and publishers and help better serve and manage offers and ads across the web. [www.cj.com/privacy_web_user.html](http://www.cj.com/privacy_web_user.html).  
Marketing | TripAdvisor (SpotLight) | The cookies allow us to monitor and enhance the performance of marketing activity via TripAdvisor. The data collected is anonymous and only used internally.  
Marketing | FloodLight | The cookies allow us to monitor and enhance the performance of marketing activity via selected third parties. The data collected is anonymous and only used internally.  
Marketing | Third Party Advertising Networks (Display Advertising) including Right Media, MediaMath, Telegraph etc | These cookies allow us to track which adverts have driven traffic to our website. The information collected by these cookies is anonymous.  
Marketing | VE Interactive | If a user enters their email address into our site (and opts in to receive emails from us), that user will receive an email suggesting a range of potential holidays based on their activity on the site. This will only happen if the user does not make a booking.  
Marketing | Criteo | Criteo shows personalised adverts when you are on some other websites based on the holidays that you've viewed on this website. The information collected by these cookies is anonymous.To opt out of receiving these cookies please visit [www.criteo.com/en/privacy-policy/opt-out](http://www.criteo.com/en/privacy-policy/opt-out).  
Marketing | Quantcast  | Helps us measure and verify the size of our audience in different parts of the world for advertising. No personally identifiable information is stored. If you would prefer not to allow Quantcast cookies, you can manage your preferences at <https://www.quantcast.com/opt-out/>  
Marketing | Adobe SiteCatalyst HBX (Hitbox) | Hitbox delivers long term tracking cookies; as part of Adobes's SiteCatalyst HBX application. More information can be found here: <https://documents.hitbox.com/optout.html>  
Marketing | Rocket Fuel | Third party provider of targeted online ad network. The cookies allow us to monitor and enhance the performance of paid-for marketing activity via selected third parties. All information collected is anonymous. For more information please visit: <http://rocketfuel.com/privacy-policy>  
Marketing | Adobe AdLens (formerly Efficient Frontier) | Adobe AdLens uses cookies to provide you with relevant content and advertising. Their technology automates the bid optimisation process and enables us to manage our search campaigns.  
Social Media | AddThis | We use AddThis to enable customers to share our site content via social media tools such as Twitter and Facebook. This cookie doesn't contain any personally identifiable information. To opt out of receiving these cookies please visit [www.addthis.com/privacy](http://www.addthis.com/privacy). The individual social networks may set their own cookies too.  
  
For more information about cookies set by our display advertising partners please visit [www.youronlinechoices.com](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/).

More information about cookies, including instructions to amend your browser settings to refuse them can be found at [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

### MONITORING

To ensure that we carry out your instructions accurately, improve our service and for security and fraud, we may review, monitor and/or record:

  1. telephone calls;
  2. activities using CCTV in and around our premises; 
  3. transactions and activities at all points of contact; and
  4. web, social media and app traffic, activities, etc.

All recordings and derivative materials are and shall remain our sole property.

### SECURITY STATEMENT

We take security very seriously. We will never send emails requesting personal details (including your passport details) or payment card details. If you get a suspicious email, don't click on any links or open any attachments. Call **020 8610 3123** and we'll investigate.

### CHANGES TO THIS POLICY

Any changes to this Policy will be either posted on our website, brochure and/or made available on request.

Privacy Policy: v July 2015
